☰ back [home](https://moneysmart.gov.au/) search

* [Follow MoneySmart on X (formerly Twitter)](https://twitter.com/moneysmartteam "Follow MoneySmart on X (formerly Twitter)")

Privacy
=======

Moneysmart privacy policy

Page reading time: 3 minutes

On this page

Any information gathered when you use the Moneysmart website and apps will not be disclosed or distributed without your consent.

We comply with the Australian Privacy Principles in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). This Act regulates the collection, storage, quality, use and disclosure of personal information. We also follow the Federal Government website guidelines issued by the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner.

The Moneysmart website is run by the Australian Securities and Investments Commission (ASIC). Please refer to [ASIC's privacy policy](https://asic.gov.au/about-asic/dealing-with-asic/privacy/asic-privacy-policy-summary/ "ASIC's privacy policy") for information about:

* how ASIC handles personal information
* your rights to seek access to and correct personal information
* how to complain about breaches of your privacy by ASIC

In the unlikely event of an investigation an attempt may be made to identify your browsing activities or personal information. In an investigation, a law enforcement agency may inspect the internet service provider's log files with a warrant.

Collection of statistical information
-------------------------------------

Moneysmart collects information, without identifying factors, for statistical and research purposes, and to help improve our tools. This information can include:

* user's server address
* top level domain name (for example, .com or .gov etc.)
* date and time of the visit
* pages accessed and documents downloaded
* responses to questions
* items added to lists
* previous site visited
* type of browser used

When preparing aggregate statistical information we may include your visit to a particular calculator or page. For example, '20% of the people who used Moneysmart's superannuation calculator explored making extra contributions to their superannuation'.

Collection, use and disclosure of personal information
------------------------------------------------------

Moneysmart will only retain your personal information with your consent, via a prominent button that you may choose to click. Any time this occurs, you will be informed of the purpose for which the information is being collected.

### Google analytics

In addition to web service logs, we use Google Analytics (including the Advertising Features), which are web analysis services provided by Google Inc. ('Google').

Reports obtained from Google Analytics are used to improve the efficiency and usability of this website. They do not contain user identifiable information. Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyse how users interact with this site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. The Advertising Features is a function within Google Analytics to get more advanced information about our users, including:

* user demographics
* user interests
* frequency of visits

For more information on how Google uses the data collected, visit [Google's Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ "Google's Privacy Policy") and [Google Analytics Terms of Service.](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/ "Google Analytics Terms of Service") To opt-out and prevent your data from being collected by Google Analytics, you can download [Google's opt out add-on.](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google's opt out add-on.")

### Moneysmart Tips enewsletter

By subscribing to Moneysmart Tips you consent to your email address being provided to Campaign Monitor, our enewsletter service provider. [Campaign Monitor's privacy policy](https://www.campaignmonitor.com/policies/ "Campaign Monitor's privacy policy") explains how they handle personal information, including their overseas storage practices.

Your email address is only used to deliver Moneysmart Tips to you. You can use an alias or generic email address. You can [access current and past editions](https://moneysmart.gov.au/subscribe-to-our-newsletter "Subscribe") of Moneysmart Tips or [unsubscribe](https://moneysmart.gov.au/subscribe-to-our-newsletter "Subscribe").

Publishing unclaimed money data
-------------------------------

Unclaimed money records are published on the Moneysmart website so people can find their lost money. This a free service offered by ASIC that people would otherwise be charged for by commercial money finding businesses. ASIC is required or authorised by law to publish this information.

Cookies
-------

This website may use cookies for online surveys. Cookies are small pieces of information exchanged between your web browser and a website server.

Internet security risks
-----------------------

The Moneysmart website employs a range of security measures to protect against data breaches, including:

* firewalls
* security patches
* regular security testing
* data encryption

This website complies with the Australian Government Protective Security Policy Framework and Information Security Manual.

As there may be security risks in sending information via the internet, you should assess these potential risks when deciding whether to use our online services.

If you have any concerns about your privacy when using this website contact us via:

* email - [\[email protected\]](https://moneysmart.gov.au/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)
* phone - 1300 300 630 (ASIC Infoline)

Do you find this page useful?

 Yes

 No

Why?

 It had the information I was looking for

 The page makes sense

 The information is balanced and unbiased

 The information gave me a sense of what to do next

Submit Any other feedback

Why not?

 It didn't have the information I was looking for

 The page was confusing

 The information overwhelmed me

 There wasn't enough information for me to take action

Submit Any other feedback

Your feedback

Your feedback relates to: Please select... Webpage Content Calculator or tool Complaint or scam Copyright requests Loans, money and personal finance advice Other feedback/suggestion

You would like to: Please select... Report an Error Comment on a Webpage Ask a question

Your issue is: Please select... You don't understand the calculator result You believe the calculator is incorrect The calculator/tool does not work (eg technical issue) You want to provide general feedback/suggestions

* **Calculator disclaimers and assumptions** can be found under each calculator. Refer to these for more detailed information about how a specific calculator works.
    
* **Calculator frequently asked questions** can be found under most calculators. Refer to these for more information.

The links below provide more information on complaints and reporting scams:

We don't lend money, arrange loans or provide personal financial advice.

If you are experiencing difficulties with money, the following pages can help:

Summary of your feedback (helps us respond faster): 

Your comments:

The page/calculator/app you are referring to (eg. cut/paste URL): 

Your email address: (if you require a reply) 

Cancel Send feedback

Up next in About us
-------------------

* [### Copyright
    
    4 min read](https://moneysmart.gov.au/about-us/copyright)
* [### Disclaimer
    
    1 min read](https://moneysmart.gov.au/about-us/disclaimer)
* [### Accessibility
    
    1 min read](https://moneysmart.gov.au/about-us/accessibility)

* [Follow MoneySmart on X (formerly Twitter)](https://twitter.com/moneysmartteam "Follow MoneySmart on X (formerly Twitter)")

 search
